Guide to the Jack Burke Jr. papers/Champions Golf Club records; 1956-2017 MS 525
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jack Burke Jr. papers/Champions Golf Club records
1956-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Burke, Jackie
MS 525
22.25 Linear Feet (25 boxes and one map drawer)
9.05 Gigabytes (Nearline access: MS525aip_001 (9.05GB)
Champions Golf Club was founded by golfing greats Jimmy Demaret and Jack Burke, Jr. in 1957 with the purpose of promoting the game of golf and bring active competition to its members and guests and to host significant national championships. The club is located north of Houston, Texas along the FM (Farmers Market road) 1960. This collection includes photographs, business papers, correspondence, news clips, and area maps from 1956 to 2007. The collection consists of 24 boxes and cartons with oversize items in a map draw. The collection is 22 linear feet.
Biographical/Historical note
In 1959 the Cypress Creek Course was opened for play, designed by Ralph Plummer. This course has hosted tournaments such as the 1967 Ryder Cup, the 1969 U.S. Open, multiple Tour Championships, the U.S. Amateur, and the Houston Champions International, which was a PGA Tour event. There are 2 courses, Cypress Creek, and Jackrabbit. The Club boasts several hundred members with single-digit handicaps, a statistic that can be matched by only a handful of other clubs in the country.
James Newton Demaret (May 24, 1910 – December 28, 1983) was an American professional golfer. He won 31 PGA Tour events in a long career between 1935 and 1957 and was the first three-time winner of the Masters.
Demaret was born in Houston, Texas. He reached his peak in the late 1940s with wins in the Masters in 1947, runner-up to Ben Hogan in the 1948 U.S. Open, and leading money winner and Vardon Trophy winner in 1947. He reached the semifinals of the PGA Championship four times in all but never won. He played on three Ryder Cup teams: 1947, 1949, and 1951. His career declined in the 1950s although he managed several key wins including the 1952 Bing Crosby Pro-Am. Demaret was elected to the World Golf Hall of Fame in 1983. In 2000, he was ranked as the 20th greatest golfer of all time by Golf Digest magazine. Known for his keen sense of humor and colorful outfits, Demaret was one of first Tour pros to become involved in golf broadcasting. After working as a commentator for "All Star Golf" in the early '60s, he replaced George Rogers as co-host for Shell's Wonderful World of Golf along with Gene Sarazen in 1966. Jimmy Demaret was a guest on "I Love Lucy" in the early 1950s. The over-70s groupings on the Senior PGA Tour were named the Friends of Demaret in his honor. He died of a heart attack in Houston, Texas as he was getting ready for a round of golf.
John Joseph "Jack" Burke, Jr. (born 29 January 1923) is an American professional golfer who was most prominent in the 1950s. He first rose to fame with two lopsided victories in the 1951 Ryder Cup matches. He was subsequently selected for the 1953, 1955, 1957, and 1959 teams, serving as playing captain in 1957. He also served as non-playing captain in the 1973 matches.
Burke was born in Fort Worth, Texas. He turned professional in 1940. He won 16 PGA Tour events in his career, including the 1956 Masters and PGA Championship. Perhaps his most famous match was his nine-hour, 40-hole quarterfinal loss to Cary Middlecoff in the 1955 PGA Championship. Burke won the Vardon Trophy for lowest scoring average in 1952 and was selected PGA Tour Player of the Year in 1956.
After retiring from competition, Burke, along with Jimmy Demaret, was the main force in creating the Houston Champions Golf Club which has been the site of many PGA Tour events, as well as the 1969 U.S. Open and 1993 U.S. Amateur. He became the fifth recipient of the PGA Tour Lifetime Achievement Award in 2003, and was inducted into the World Golf Hall of Fame in 2000. Burke shares his permanent locker at Augusta National Golf Club, home of The Masters in Augusta, Georgia with Tiger Woods. As tradition dictates, both keep their prized green jackets, awarded to the annual winner of the tournament, in a wooden, finished locker with gold name plates on the front, with each year listed for the year they won.
Sources:
Rule, Bob (with forward by Ben Hogan) (1976). "Champions Golf Club 1957-1976".
Page/International Communications, United States. 2003, second edition.
Champions Golf Club (April 2, 2009). Retrieved April 27, 2009 from http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Champions_Golf_Club
Jimmy Demart (April 21, 2009). Wikipedia. Retrieved April 27, 2009 from http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Demaret.
Jack Burke Jr. (April 21, 2009). Wikipedia. Retrieved April 27, 2009 from http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Burke_Jr.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes the business records associated with Champions Golf Club located in the area of Houston, Texas. The club was founded by pro golfers Jimmy Demaret and Jack Burke, Jr. in 1957 with the purpose of promoting the game of golf and bringing active competition to its members and guests and to host significant national championships. This collection includes photographs, business papers, correspondence, news clips, and area maps from 1956 to 2007. Subject areas include golf course design, the logistics of hosting local and national competitions, photographs of celebrity guests including Hollywood stars, and information about club-related subdivisions. The collection is in excellent condition. It consists of 24 boxes and cartons with oversize items in a map draw. The collection is 22 linear feet.
Access Restrictions
Most of the material in this collection is not restricted. However, some files in box 7 are restricted. Consult with an archivist at the Woodson Research Center. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586. Allow 24 hours retrieval time.
Acquisition Information
Jack Burke Jr. and the Champions Golf Club donated this collection to the Woodson Research Center in Rice University's Fondren Library.
Index Terms
Subjects
Golf courses -- United States; Golf course architects; Sports
Subjects (Persons)
Burke, Jackie
Subjects (Corporations)
Champions Golf Club; Champions Golf Club
- Series I: Photos
  - Jack Burke, Jr.; envelope 1 of 2 (Box 1, Envelope 1)
    General note
    large format
  - Jack Burke, Jr.; envelope 2 of 2 (Box 1, Envelope 2)
  - Jack Burke, Jr. and Celebrities (Box 1, Envelope 3)
  - Jack Burke, Jr. and others (Box 1, Envelope 4)
  - Jack Burke, Sr; Jack Burke, Jr. and brother; Jack Burke, Jr. and sons (Box 1, Envelope 5)
  - Jack Burke, Jr. military, 1940s (Box 1, Envelope 6)
  - Jack Burke, Jr. and Jimmy Demeret (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jack Burke, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burke family (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Blessing the grounds (golf course), circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Caddies (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cart barn fire (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Casino party (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Christmas Decorating, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cookbook images (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Course views (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jack Crouse; Maui News, undate (Box 1, Envelope 17)
  - Jimmy Demeret (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Duos, Trios, Groups of Players (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - FM 1960 Area (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Gallery (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gallery (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Golf club house and pool area (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Groups (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Individuals (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ladies events (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Leader board (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Party photographs; folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Party photographs; folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Teams (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Tokyo (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Tournaments; folder 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tournaments; folder 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Trophy presentations (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Negatives (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Positives and negatives of golfers (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chapions Gold Club, 1957-2006, 50th Anniversary; a portfolio of fine art prints from the original paintings by Kenneth Reed FRSA; Members' Edition (Box 4)
  - Journal; membership list including Honorary members and Resident members., circa 1964 (Box 4)
    Journal insert -- the journal also contains loose lists, probably of members. The lists is enclosed in an envelope and tucked itno the Journal.
  - Jack Burke, no date (Box 4)
    Format: SP 60 Broadcast videocassette, 3M Color Plus for use on U-matic SP equipment.
  - 1993 Interview with Jack Burke Jr. before the U.S. Amateur Championship. (Box 4)
    Format: VHS, 3M T-60, video tape.
  - Champions Golf Club 23rd annual member-guest tournament "Out of Africa" invitation, October 1-3, 1987. (Box 4)
    Format: Paper tube with paper inserts.
  - Membership ledger, 1959-1965 (Box 4)
  - Membership ledger, 1981-2001 (Box 4)
  - General Journal, July 1959-1966 (Box 4)
    The General Journal is a ledge related to the income and expenses of operating Champions Golf Club.
  - Ryder Cup Dinner menu, October 18, 1967 (Box 4)
    Front cover has the name "Mr. Lloyd Lambert" inscribed.
  - Scrapbook pages with news clips and correspondence, 1961 (Box 4)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1961-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, U.S. Open, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Commissioner Bob Eckels, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence regarding Champions name, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Regarding Champions name, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence Regarding Champions name, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence regarding Champions name, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - Sherry Freed, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence - Shirley Sembritzky, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Series III: Business files
  The business files of Champions Golf Club contains information related to daily operations, sporting events, membership, finances, and club activities.
  - Second 18-Hole Course Estimates and Preliminary Work, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Second 18-Hole Course, March 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Second 18-Hole Course Construction C.F. Thomas and Co., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Second 18-Hole Course C.F. Thomas and Co., 1964-65 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Second 18-Hole Course Texas Construction Material Co., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Second 18-Hole Course, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Spring Branch Savings and Loan Lease and Loan, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Texas National Bank Furnishings Loan, 1958-59 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Long Point National Bank Loan, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Texas Commerce Bank Loan, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Texas Commerce Bank Loan, 1988-89 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Spring Bank Savings and Loan Loan, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Jack Burke Loan, no date (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Fixed Asset Adjustments, January 31, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - State Securities Board, no date (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - State Securities Board, 1958-62 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Security Commissioner, 1957-59 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Appraisals, no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Art Works Inventory, 1987-89 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Art Fund, no date (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Art Works Appraisal, October 10 1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Insurance, no date (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Property Tax Receipts, no date (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Federal Excise Tax, 1957-65 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Franchise Tax, 1959-65 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - U.S. Dept. of Commerce Census of Business, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Norman Lumber and Supply, 1959-61 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Securities Exchange App. for Exemption from Registration, no date (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Jack Burke Interview, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Tour Championship (Southern Co.), folder 1 of 2, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tour Championship (Southern Co.), folder 2 of 2, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tour Championship, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tour Championship (Coca Cola), November 3-9, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Houston/Champions International Tournament, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Nabisco Golf Championships, October 22-28, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Houston/Champions International Tournament, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Houston/Champions International Tournament, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Yeager Playground, 1998-2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - USGA Golfing Rules, 1964-1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Champions Recognition Study, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - George Fazio, Architect for 2nd course, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Tax analysis, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Legal fees anaylysis, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Course Rankings, 1994, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Water treatment, 1967-1968, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Income tax returns, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    This file is restricted until 2019.
  - Financial reports, 1993-2004 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Auditors reports, Champions Golf Club, Inc., 1992, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Financial statements, Septemeber 1992, April 1994-October 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. monthly [financial] comparisons, 1989-1999 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Golf club discrimination against women; news clips, 1991, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Champions Celebrity Colony and Champions Trail Golf Development, 2000, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Employee handbook, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - New member information, roster, club brochure, circa 1957-2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Eulogy for Jimmy Demaret by Father Larry Connelly, January 6, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Gifts and donations, 2002, 2003-2004, undated. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Newsclips, 1939-1997 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Open, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - News clips; International Golf Tournament, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Houston/Champions International Golf Tournament, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - The European Club at Brittas Bay, Wicklow, Ireland, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Proposed 2001 tournament schedule--27 holes, undated. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Deeds, warranties,surveys, 1961, 1971, 1975. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Development, 1961-1963, 1965. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Business profile and auditors report, 1993, 1995. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Articles of incorporation, 1957. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Stock prospectus, 1965, 1991. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Stock prospectus, circa 1984. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Texas Banc Savings - stock, 1989-1990. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Trademark Registration, 1976, 1989-1998. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Horace Hunter Norman Sale to Champions, 1962-1977. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Champions Glen Subdvision, circa 2004. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Cypresswood Drive property, 1990. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Club renovations, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Texas Liquor Control Board audits, 1963-1966. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Inventory - Golf Course Equipment, circa 1960s. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Irrigation System - Clubhouse, 1987. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Texas Water Wells, Inc. Completion Report on Water Well I, June 1963. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Tom Robbins bio and photocopied images, circa 1964. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Ryder Cup, 2004-2005/. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - USGA Turb Advisory report, 1990. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - USGA site questionnaire, March 1997. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Mission, membership welcome booklet, circa 1969. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Golf course maintenance, March 2004. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - FM 1960 Sound attenuation wall, 1984-1987, undated. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - George Fazio bridge memorial marker, 2000. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Weekley and Valenti, Inc. advertising, loan, and public relations about Champions opening, 1956-1968. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - USGA correspondence, 1975-1989. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Benjamin page Survey, 10 acres on Champions Dr, insurance deed, 1976. (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Survey, 1991. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Champions Charity Foundation, 1983-1984. (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Goleman and Rolfe Associates, Inc. drawings and layout of Champions clubhouse, circa 1956-1960s. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Bogus member/guest charges, 1991-1992. (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Touche, Nevin, Bailey and Smart account statements, circa 1958-1959. (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Raveneaux tree removal, April, June 1988. (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Manager's house deeds and contracts, 1959-1960 1965, 1967. (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - West Sports Marketing and Champions of Golf Series, 1993-1998. (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Membership, 1965-1999. (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Handicapp index, 1999, 2000. (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Golf resort brochure examples, circa 1985. (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Champions tournement programs, 1967-2003. (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Tournement played at Champions, 1999. (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Champions newsletters, 1991-2004. (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Golfing magazines with mentions of Jack Burke or Champions (including Burke's swing), 1952-1996. (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Champions wine list, circa 1960-2004. (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - 69th U.S. Open Championships, statistics, 1969. (Box 8, Folder 45)
    The pages in this folder were contained within a dark green vinyl binder with the title in gold lettering: IBM Sports Information Services and 69th U.S. Open Championship James Demaret.
  - "Times on the Game of Golf" from Jack Burke, Sr., 1985. (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Board meeting minutes., 1957-1959. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Board meeting minutes., 1960-1969. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Board meeting minutes., 1970-1979. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting minutes., 1980-1989. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting minutes., 1990-1999. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting minutes., 2000-2007. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Shareholder and board materials., 1961-2004. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Champions Golf Club (Houston) versus The Champions Golf Club (Nicholasville), 1997-1998. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Jimmy Demaret contract for International Golf Show, New York, 1964. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Champions Concession Agreement with Jack Burke, 1989, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Agreements - Burke and Demaret, 1965, 1973. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Riverside Golf Club, Inc.; folder 1 of 5, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Riverside Golf Club, Inc.; folder 2 of 5, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Riverside Golf Club, Inc.; folder 3 of 5, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Riverside Golf Club, Inc.; folder 4 of 5, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Riverside Golf Club, Inc.; folder 5 of 5, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bennett G. and Nancy C. Fisher versus Jack Burke, Jr., 2004. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Economy Gas Inc, and Joe Haven versus Jack Burke and Jimmy Demaret, 1993,1996. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. (Houston) versus The Champions Golf Club, Inc. (Nicholasville); 1993-1997, xxxxxxxxx. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Eagle Run West Golf Partnership, 2003. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Champions Golf Club, Inc. versus Sunrise Land Corp. et al, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Legal battles involving the name "Champions", 1978,1987, 1993. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - legal, 1992-2000. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Ralph Plummer Architect contract, 1957. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Eddie Condon's souvenir photo with Jimmy Burke, circa 1950-1960s. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Souvenir photo from Concord, Kiamesha Lake, New York, circa 1960s. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Pictured in photo are Jimmy Demaret, Jacke Burke Jr., a woman who may be Burke's wife, and two other men.
  - Aerials and ground negatives, hand drawn map, February [25], 1961. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - J. Burke and J. Demaret with 3 ladies, Burke with membership card, negatives, March 7, 1957. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jacie Burke at the Houston Club, negatives, March 1, 1957. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Jackie Burke at the Houston Club, negatives, March 1, 1957. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Burke and Demaret on golf course, February 12, 1957. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Burke, Demaret with celebrities: Phil Harris, Dean Martin, Bob Hope and others, negatives, February 11, 1957. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jack Burke, Jimmy Demaret with golf course design, negatives, February 9, 19[57]. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - aerials of [Champions] golf course, negatives, March 18, 1958. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Burke, Demart, and Gordon McRae on course progress of club house, negatives, October 1958. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Champions Golf Course aerial views, negatives, September 16, [1955-1960]. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Burke adn Demaret at Champions Golf Club, negatives, July 1957. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Aerial views of Champions Golf Club, negatives, January 1960. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Demaret, Burke and [Bob] Hogan at golf club, negatives, March 7, 1957. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Tournament unknown, crowd, aerial and family, positives, circa 1957-1980s. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - jack Burke and friends, photocopies of photos from 1940s, correspondence from Bobby Brown, August 3, 2002. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Van Wie, Pinehurst, N.C., circa 1927; photo, undated. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Skip Alexander, Ben Hogan, Jack Burke; photo, undated. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Bob Hope and Arnold Palmer; color photo, circa 1998-2003. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Photo is encased in cellophane-like material with handwritten note reading "Mr. Burke Enjoy! Parr [unclear signature]."
  - First introduction of night golf in 1951 at Lloyd's Golf Course, Portland Ore.; photo, circa 1951. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Jimmy Burke Jr. at leader board, 1952. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Jack Burke, Jr. at Tam O'Shanter Golf Tournament, circa 1950-1960s. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Portrait of Jimmy Demaret by Murray Olderman for the book "My Partner, Ben Hogan", circa 1954. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - 1980 Major thoroughfare and freeway plan, Houston City Planning Commission (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Series IV: Oversize
  - topographic and survey maps of Champions Golf Course and areas (Map-drawer 50, Folder -)
- Series V: Cup Matches, 1966 - 2006
  - Cup matches, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Cup matches sponsors, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Cup matches invitation correspondence, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Cup matches club champions, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cup matches reader file, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Cup matches letter of information, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Cup matches thank you letters, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Cup matches, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Cup matches contestants, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Cup matches pairings, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Champions Cup Invitational questionnaires, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 11)